euromedalex.org 2019-04-26

# Privacy Policy | Anna Lindh Foundation

At the Anna Lindh Foundation (the “Foundation”) we take the protection of your data very seriously.

This policy (and our data protection documents and internal policies we are updating in compliance with the Regulation (EU) 2016/679 of 27 April 2016, the so-called General Data Protection Regulation (the “GDPR”)) explains when and why we collect personal information about people who visit our website, how we use it, the conditions under which we may disclose it to others and how we keep it secure.

Please, note that we may change this policy from time to time to be up-to-date and fully compliant with the GDPR and, in general, with data protection practice. Therefore, check this page occasionally to be aware of any changes and to ensure that you agree with them. 

##  Who are we?

The Foundation was created by the governments of the Euro-Mediterranean Partnership, the far-reaching political agreement established in 1995 between the European Union and its Southern Mediterranean partners.

It is an organisation shared and resourced by forty-two Euro-Mediterranean countries, to bring people together as a way to promote dialogue between cultures and respect for diversity.  
To fulfil this objective, the Foundation leads regional initiatives in the Euro-Med space and supports local activities carried out by organisations based across civil society which advocate for a better understanding among people, religions and beliefs, and champion human rights and democracy.  
According to the GDPR, the Foundation is the Data Controller. We are on the way to designate a Data Protection Officer.

##  What information is collected from you?

We will only use your data to provide our services (e.g. getting the Foundation’s newsletter, informing you about the Foundation’s projects, events and initiatives, and potential opportunities).

Please, note that we will process your data only after you decide if you will give the Foundation your consent.

If you give us your consent, the Foundation will process your name, email address, postal address and phone number to communicate to you according to your preferences.

If you have only subscribed to the Foundation’s newsletter, then your email address and your name are the only details we store from you.

If you have sent us your résumé, we process information therein.

##  What is our legal basis?

Our lawful basis for processing your data is your consent.

If you do not give us your consent or decide to withdraw your consent at any time, we will not start to process your data or we will stop to process your data in accordance with Article 7 of the GDPR.

##  How do we collect information from you?

We obtain information about you when you use our website, for example, when you register to join the Foundation, contact us about our services or when apply for an event and/or initiative.

##  Who has access to your information?

The Foundation acting as Data Controller accesses to your personal data.

The Foundation’s employees are entitled to access your personal data as they act under the authority of the Foundation. They process your data following the Foundation’s instructions.

Please, note that we will not sell, rent or share your information to third parties without your prior consent.

##  How you can access and update your information

The accuracy of your personal data is very important to us.

You may request to access to your personal data the Foundation process by sending an email to [info@annalindhfoundation.org](mailto:info@annalindhfoundation.org).

We’re working on ways to make it easier for you to review and correct your personal data that we hold about you. In the meantime, if you change email address, or any of the other information we hold is inaccurate or out of date, please email us at [info@annalindhfoundation.org](mailto:info@annalindhfoundation.org).
